Inventory of the Charles Campbell Papers 1743-1896
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Family and Professional Papers (Box 2-17)
  - Letters, 1860-1869., 259 items. (Box 12-14)
    - Letters, 1866., 14 items. (Box-folder 13:25-38)
      - [Charles] Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to [?], New York, 30 October 18[6]6., 1 page. ADfS. (Box-folder 13:37)
        Letter pertains to Campbell's efforts to get information about a manuscript which he submitted to Harpers. Manuscript recommended to Harpers by Rev. Dr. James W. Alexander.
      - A[nna] C[ampbell], Park Side, Riverdale to Charles [Campbell], 13 November 1866., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 13:38)
        Visited Rahway and New York; got new clothes; looking for the meteor shower.
    - Letters, 1867., 49 items. (Box-folder 13:39-87)
      - Information on the Burk Family, [c. 1867]., 3 pages. Ms. (Box-folder 13:39)
      - Nanny Campbell, Trenton, New Jersey to "Pa" [Charles Campbell], [c. 1867]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:40)
        Is keeping a diary; went to the dentist and had teeth pulled. Anna C[ampbell] to Charles [Campbell]. Went to the dentist; house-keeping instructions.
      - [Charles Campbell] to [?], [1867]., 2 pages. Incomplete. ADf. (Box-folder 13:41)
        Examines the question of the "Negro"; argues that Negroes are innately inferior, and that once freed of constraints, will inevitably regress to "indolence and barbarism" in their native state. Presents the argument that black slaves brought to America because white laborers couldn't withstand sun in the South. [Grouped with letters of Buckner H. Payne to Campbell of July 29, 1867; August 10, 1867; August 22, 1867. Payne an author of Ariel, a pamphlet on the Negro, for which he had solicited Campbell's opinion. This draft may be part of the reply.].
      - R[obert] L[ewis] Dabney to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 28 January 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:42)
        Inquires into efforts by colonial House of Burgesses to exclude the slave trade. Asks for reference in Hening to Revolutionary charge that the King had endeavored to arm slaves against the colonists.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 9 April 1867., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 13:43)
        Inquires into the history of the early settlement of Newport News.
      - E[lizabeth] M. Maben, Richmond to Charles [Campbell], 1 June 1867., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 13:44)
        Mildred [last name?] expects to marry June 6. Invites him and Anna to wedding. Mr. Maben's health very poor.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 24 June 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:45)
        Gives him a quote from George Mason on the slave trade. Compliments him on his recent article on Pocahontas. Speaks of other books he has seen.
      - Anna Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to "Mother", 11 July 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:46)
        Charles Campbell sick; servant left; garden ripening.
      - R. Barnett, Vicksburg, Mississippi to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 12 July 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:47)
        Information on James B. Burk.
      - Tho[ma]s H. Wynne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 13 July 1867., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 13:48)
        Next Tuesday he is meeting the president of the Maryland Historical Society for a tour of Yorktown and the vicinity. Asks him to join them.
      - Buckner H. Payne, Nashville to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 29 July 1867., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 13:49)
        Sent Campbell a pamphlet on "The Negro", which was to be widely distributed, north and south. Asked for Campbell's opinion of the work.
      - J[unia] [A.] Burk, Baton Rouge to [Charles Campbell], August 1867., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:50)
        Information on Burk family.
      - Junia A. Burk, Baton Rouge, to [Charles] Campbell, 2 August 1867., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:51)
        Information on John D. Burk.
      - Charles Deane, Cambridge to Charles Campbell, 2 August 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:52)
        Deane, who is printing Captain John Smith's last will and testament, asks for particulars of a book by Washington W. Smyth, cited in Charles Campbell's History of Virginia. Cites an error in Charles Campbell's volume. Added note in Charles Campbell's hand gives citation for his date. Deane will print other early papers. Added note on Smyth's book.
      - B[uckner] W. Payne, Nashville to Campbell, 10 August 1867., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:53)
        A discussion of Payne's Ariel, a pamphlet examining negroes. Different opinions upon it and a discussion of anti-slavery attitudes. Mentions Henry Ward Beecher, Mandell Phillips, Charles Sumner, Horace Greeley.
      - B[uckner] H. Payne, Nashville to Campbell, 22 August 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:54)
        Examination of the negroe question in light of Biblical history, and also science (Prof. Aggassiz).
      - Charles Deane, Cambridge to Charles Campbell, 23 August 1867., 8 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:55)
        Thanks for letter and enclosure of the 8th. Extended comparisons of the various accounts of Captain John Smith's rescue from the Indians and Pocahontas' part in that rescue, including primary and secondary accounts. Deane concludes that Smith exaggerated and embellished the story over time. Asks whether "corn" refers to shelled Indian corn.
      - Sally Braxton Slaughter [?], Hazel Hill to Charles [Campbell], 27 August 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:56)
        Offers him a place to live.
      - Anna [Campbell], Trenton, New Jersey to Charles [Campbell], 28 August 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:57)
        Had good trip; wishes he and Charlie could join them.
      - Dennis Jones, Baton Rouge, Louisiana to [Charles] Campbell, 30 August [c. 1867]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:58)
        Thanks him for his interest in J. D. Burk; Louisiana offers little future for him; Lt. Governor is a former slave; expects that "a gentleman and a Southerner will soon be debarred from all rights whatsoever," asks Charles Campbell to help get him a job in Petersburg.
      - [Mary Campbell] to "Father" [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia, 1 September [c. 1867]., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 13:59)
        Has seen several Quakers. Also: Anna [Campbell] to Charles [Campbell]. Does not feel well; has given the children medicine; going to a china factory; has received all the money due for 1867.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Lawrenceville, New Jersey to Charles [Campbell], 10 September 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:60)
        Expects to go to Port Chester; sends catsup recipe. Mary [Campbell] to Charles Campbell. Is making him slippers in size six.
      - W[illia]m W[irt] Henry, Charlotte Co[urt] Ho[use], Virginia to Charles Campbell, 11 September 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:61)
        Asks for Charles Campbell's article on Patrick Henry.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Anna [Campbell],13 September 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:62)
        Went to Chelsea; fired the cook.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg to W[illia]m W[irt] Henry,14 September 1867., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 13:63)
        Sends him an article published in Richmond Dispatch. Is happy to learn he possesses documents which will "vindicate" his grandfather, Patrick Henry.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Port Chester, [New York] to Charles [Campbell], 17 September 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:64)
        Went to Rye Beach; will visit New York; hopes he will consider carefully before resigning his present position; hopes they will move north.
      - Charles Deane, Cambridge, Massachusetts to [Charles Campbell, Petersburg], 17 September 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:65)
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Geo[rge] H. Moore, 20 September 1867., 1 page. ACy. (Box-folder 13:66)
        Is preparing a memoir of John D. Burk; asks for data on Burk.
      - Nanny Campbell, Portchester, New York to "Pa" [Charles Campbell], 22 September [1867?]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:67)
        Enjoying her visit; Cousin Jane will send Charlie a "star baseball"; went to a Friends meeting; hopes he will not work himself out working at a "dull school." Also: Anna [Campbell] to Charles Campbell. Housekeeping instructions.
      - Anna [Campbell], Port Chester, [New York] to Charles [Campbell], 22 September 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:68)
        Still at Cousin Jane's; would like Charlie to go to school; went to Friends meeting; sends a pudding recipe.
      - Geo[rge] H. Moore, New York to Charles Campbell, 24 September 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:69)
        Has found no new materials on Burk; has been attacked for his history of slavery.
      - A. W. Miller, Charlotte, North Carolina to Charles Campbell, 25 September 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:70)
        Returns a copy of Dr. Rile's magazine.
      - [?], Purchase, New York to "Pennsylvania," 28 September 1867., 4 pages. AL. (Box-folder 13:71)
        Enjoying her visit; went to a Friends meeting.
        Letter also includes a letter of 8 October 1867. Anna C[ampbell], Harlem, [New York] to Charles [Campbell]. Hopes Charlie has begun school; housekeeping instructions; sent him clothes. ALS. pages.
      - Nanny Campbell, Portchester, New York to "Pa" [Charles Campbell], 1 October 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:72)
        Went to a country fair; will be home October 20; hopes to go to New York City.
        Letter also includes a letter from Anna [Campbell] to Charles Campbell. Expects to go to Harlem.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Charles Deane, 3 October 1867., 1 page. ADfS. (Box-folder 13:73)
        Thanks for copies of Bacon's and Ingram's Rebellion.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to George H. Moore, 3 October 1867., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 13:74)
        Thanks him for article on slavery; making up a Spotswood genealogy.
      - J[unia] [A.] Burk, Baton Rouge to C[harles] Campbell, 4 October 1867., 11 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:75)
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, Virginia to [Charles Campbell], 10 October 1867., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:76)
        Gives answers to various questions asked by Campbell in a letter of 4 October 1867. Encourages him to publish a "Spottswood Genealogy." Tells him to retain his teaching job while maintaining his writing efforts.
      - Junia [A.] Burk, Baton Rouge to C[harles] Campbell, 13 October 1867., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:77)
      - Mildred W. Campbell, Richmond to Charles [Campbell], 19 October 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:78)
        Informs him of her intention to return home shortly.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to [?], 24 October 1867., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 13:79)
        Asks for data on Dandridge family.
      - Mary [Campbell], Riverdale to Charly [Charles Campbell, Jr.], 26 October [c. 1867]., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:80)
        Ma bought him a baseball; went to Barnum's museum; went to Central Park.
        Letter also includes another from Anna C[ampbell] to Charles [Campbell]. Expects to go to Harlem and then come home; Fall foliage beautiful.
      - [Charles Campbell] to [Charles Deane], 6 November 1867., 1 page. NDf. (Box-folder 13:81)
        Thanks for copies of Capt. John Smith's Last Will and Testament, and the Seal of the Council for New England. Refers to discrepancy in Smith's age. Believes Smith was a greater man than Sir Walter Raleigh.
      - J[unia] B[urk], Baton Rouge to [Charles] Campbell, 16 November 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:82)
      - W[illiam] B. Harrison, Brandon to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 2 December 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:83)
        Harrison family data.
      - J[unia] [A.] Burk, Baton Rouge to [Charles] Campbell, 2 December 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:84)
        Information on J. D. Burk.
      - [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, Virginia to Junia A. Burk, 11 December 1867., 2 pages. ACy. (Box-folder 13:85)
        Received her manuscript.
      - W[illia]m Wirt Henry, Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse] to Charles Campbell, 21 December 1867., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 13:86)
        Asks for information on Patrick Henry.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to Armistead Curtis, 26 December 1867., 2 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 13:87)
        Asks for information on Armistead Curtis's family and Burk family.
    - Letters, 1868., 57 items. (Box-folder 14:1-57)
      - Junia [A.] Burk, Baton Rouge to [Charles] Campbell, 21 January 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:1)
      - Mary Ann Pyne, Richmond, Virginia to Charles Campbell, 5 February 1868., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 14:2)
        Would like a copy of History of John Daly Burk.
      - J[unia] [A.] Burk, Baton Rouge to [Charles] Campbell, 18 February 1868., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:3)
        Sends more data on J. D. Burk.
      - T. D. Davidson and John Dorman[?], [Petersburg] to Cha[rle]s Campbell, [Petersburg], 2 March 1868., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 14:4)
        Informs him that the has been chosen one of the visitors of the Tabb Street Sabbath School.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to J. Munsell, 28 March 1868., 2 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 14:5)
        Has prepared the index for Burk book; "The Pan-Africans flourish in this bailiwick like the green baby tree."
      - Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin to Ch[arle]s Campbell, [Petersburg], 31 March 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:6)
        Asks about details of the sword of Gen. George Rogers Clark, mentioned in the History of Virginia. Sends him some pamphlets on the State Historical Society of Wisconsin.
      - R. H. Smith, Jr., Scotland Neck to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 2 April 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:7)
        Curtis family data.
      - James M. Keller, Memphis, Tennessee to Charles [Campbell], 20 April 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:8)
        Believes Charles Campbell is writing a book on Civil War and asks for a copy; asks for family genealogy; Mary F. Keller well but is not really convinced that the slaves have been freed or that the war is really over; James M. Keller is in charge of Memphis City Hospital.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to P. A. Spotswood, 4 May 1868., 3 pages. ACyS. (Box-folder 14:9)
        Spotswood genealogy will be published soon; asks for data on Spotswood family.
      - W[illia]m Preston Johnston, J .J. White, Edw[ar]d S. Joynes, Lexington, Virginia to [Charles Campbell], 6 May 1868., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 14:10)
        Invitation to commencement of Washington College.
      - Crozier Keller, Memphis, Tennessee to Cha[rle]s Campbell, 7 May 1868., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:11)
        Genealogy; has recently married; family news.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg to Lyman C. Draper, [Madison, Wisconsin], 20 May 1868., 1 page. Draft. AL. (Box-folder 14:12)
        Does not recall his source for information on George Rogers Clark's sword. Thanks him for pamphlets.
      - Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia to William Preston Johnston, J. J. White, Edward S. Joynes, 26 May 1868., 1 page. ACyS. (Box-folder 14:13)
        Declines invitation to attend commencement of Washington College.
      - J. Munsell, Albany to [Charles] Campbell, 4 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:14)
        Has lost the Burk will; wants booksellers to order copies of Burk book from him.
      - Charles Deane, Cambridge, Massachusetts to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 5 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:15)
        Thanks him for the books he sent; discusses historical questions connected with them.
      - Mary A[nn] Pyne, Louisville, Kentucky to Charles Campbell, 6 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:16)
        Received copy of memoir of Burk; family history data.
        Letter also includes a letter from 18 June 1868. ALS. 2 pages.
      - G. W. Fahnestock, Philadelphia to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 6 June 1868., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:17)
        Mr. Fahnestock, a collector of pamphlets, acknowledged receipt of packet of pamphlets from Campbell. Had a possible purchase in Boston of collection of 10,000 pamphlets.
      - W[illia]m Green, Richmond, [Virginia] to Charles Campbell, 10 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:18)
        Has read the materials for memoir of J. D. Burk.
      - G. W. Fahnestock, Philadelphia to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 12 June 1868., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:19)
        Received copies of Memoirs of John Daly Burk and the Genealogy of the Spotswood Family. Refers to Major Robert Stobo, whom Campbell sought letters by.
      - J[unia] A. Burk, Baton Rouge to [Charles] Campbell, 16 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:20)
        Received the manuscript package.
      - Junia A. Burk, Baton Rouge to [Charles] Campbell, 19 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:21)
        Received the package he sent.
      - Hugh B. Grigsby, Edgehill to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 20 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:22)
        He has been quite sick. Speaks of a connection between the Spotswood and Grigsby families.
      - H. C. Alexander, Charlotte Co[urt] House, to Charles Campbell, 22 June 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:23)
        Thanks him for his letter and funny pictures.
      - G. W. Fahnestock, Bangor to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 25 June 1868., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:24)
        Has put an assistant to work tracing information on Gov. Spotswood. Relates impressions of libraries in Boston area.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell,[Warrenton], to Charles [Campbell], 27 June 1868., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:25)
        Acknowledges receipt of his Genealogy of the Spotswood Family and Memoirs of [John Daly] Burke. Sorry to hear he will lose his present position. Social news of various former Confederate soldiers now farming in Warrenton.
      - Crozier Keller, Shelby, Alabama to Charles Campbell, 5 July [1868]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:26)
        Thanks Charles Campbell for the Genealogy; death of Arthur Henley, killed by "bushwackers and their wives"; family news.
      - A[lexander] S. Campbell to Charles [Campbell], 8 July 1868., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:27)
        Fears letter of 27th of June 1868 was lost and undelivered. Therefore he conveys same news as was in that letter.
      - Anna C[ampbell] to Charles [Campbell], 26 July 1868., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:28)
        Hopes his head can be healed.
      - Inventory of books of Anderson Seminary by Charles Campbell, 9 August 1868., 1 page. Ms. (Box-folder 14:29)
      - G. W. Fahnestock, Philadelphia to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 17 August 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:30)
        Responding to Campbell's inquiry for information about burial place of Gov. Spotswood. Had not yet discovered the info. Refers to a Mr. Kidder of North England Historical and Genealogical Society.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Port Chester, [New York] to Charles [Campbell], 17 August 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:31)
        Has had influenza; house cleaning instructions.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Port Chester, New York to Charles [Campbell], 22 August 1868., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:32)
        Glad he is feeling better; for Charles Campbell teaching is a "great burden" and has prayed he would be relieved of it; urges him to apply to be high school principal; urges him to put his trust in God.
      - W[illia]m Campbell, Richmond to Cha[rle]s Campbell, 25 August 1868., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 14:33)
        Sends prospectus of new magazine, and solicits a short historical piece on the "late war," (Civil War) for their first number in September. Sends advertisement for magazine from the Farmer's Gazette.
      - Crozier Keller, "Cottage Grove," Alabama to Charles Campbell, 1 September [1868]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:34)
        Encloses picture of Charles Campbell's mother; family news; Dr. James Keller is "the most desponding democrat I know" and fears "a war of races" if Brownlows's militia bill passes; hopes Presidential election will be peaceful.
      - C[harles] C[ampbell], [Jr.], Port Chester, [New York] to "Pa" [Charles Campbell]. 3 September 1868. (Box-folder 14:35)
        Went to a circus; went swimming.
        Letter also includes an item of 6 September 1868. Anna Campbell to Charles [Campbell]. Is visiting Elewood's and is planning to visit several others. 4 pages.
      - Mildred W. Campbell, Spotswood to Charles [Campbell], 3 September 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:36)
        Letter received from Ann; sick with a cold. Speaks of a debt to Mr. McClandish.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Port Chester, [New York] to Charles [Campbell], 7 September 1868., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:37)
        Someone else had been appointed to take Charles Campbell's place at Anderson Seminary feels God will help them and provide; suggests opening a book store in Fauquier; Fanny buried in Fauquier.
      - Herbert A. Claiborne, Richmond to Charles Campbell, 12 September 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:38)
        Data on Dandridge family.
      - T[homas] H. Wynne, Baltimore to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, 15 September 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:39)
        Is sorry to hear of his misfortunes. Asks for another copy of the Spotswood Genealogy; he will pay him for it later.
      - W. Winston Fontaine, Richmond, Virginia to Charles [Campbell], 15 September 1868., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:40)
        Tells him of a job vacancy; asks about Aylett family genealogy.
      - Mildred W. Campbell, Spotswood to Charles [Campbell], [Warrenton?], 16 September 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:41)
        Family news. Letter received from Anna Campbell, informing her of son's lack of success at finding employment.
      - Anna C[ampbell], Harlem, [New York] to Charles [Campbell], 16 September 1868., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:42)
        Charles Campbell against the "Warrenton scheme" and Anna Campbell regrets it and is not certain of the boarding house idea; Mary and Nanny should pack.
      - [Anna Campbell], Fauquier County, Virginia to Charles [Campbell], 16 September 1868., 4 pages. Incomplete. AL. (Box-folder 14:43)
        Teaching the children reading and sewing; Charles Campbell should put his faith in God to provide; is reading the Gospels.
      - Mildred W. Campbell, Spotswood to Charles [Campbell], [Warrenton?], 23 September 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:44)
        Speaks of Charles' moving. Says she does not know where she will live after this move. Speaks of his sending some books to Callaway.
      - W. Winston Fontaine, Fredericksburg, Virginia to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, Virginia, 26 September 1868., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:45)
        Received the Spotswood Genealogy. Judge Coleman has been away and therefore W. Winston Fontaine could not find out about the vacancy in his school for Charles Campbell; is preparing to open his school.
      - M[ildred] W. C[ampbell], Spotswood to Charles [Campbell], [Petersburg], 26 September 1868., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:46)
        Glad to learn Anna (wife) and Charley (son) are home safely. Approves of possible move to Baltimore by Charles Campbell.
      - James Wood Davidson, Columbia, South Carolina Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 10 October 1868., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 14:47)
        Asks for personal information and list of books published by Charles Campbell for inclusion in a work on living writers of the South.
      - [Anna Campbell], Shirley to Charles [Campbell], 12 October 1868., 4 pages. Incomplete. AL. (Box-folder 14:48)
        Children have colds.
      - M[ary] S[potswood] C[ampbell], Shirley to "Father" [Charles Campbell], 14 October 1868., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 14:49)